Register of the Latvian subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Latvian Subject Collection
1940-2014
XX811
Hoover Institution Archives
17 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (7.5 linear feet)
Serial issues, election campaign literature, bulletins, newsletters, pamphlets, other printed matter, and video tapes, relating to various aspects of Latvian history, and especially to the movement culminating in re-establishment of Latvian independence in 1991, and to subsequent Latvian politics and elections.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Serial issues, election campaign literature, bulletins, newsletters, pamphlets, other printed matter, and video tapes, relating to various aspects of Latvian history, and especially to the movement culminating in re-establishment of Latvian independence in 1991, and to subsequent Latvian politics and elections.
Elections--Latvia.; Latvia--History.; Latvia--Politics and government.; Latvia.; Nationalism--Latvia.; Soviet Union.
- Subject File, 1945-1994 (Box 1-2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Articles, clippings, reports, printed matter, leaflets, and other materials. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Latvia
    - General (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Commerce. Latvian Export Directory, 1993 (Folder 2)
    - Description. Sinka, Juris, Latvia and Latvians, London, 1988 (Folder 3)
    - Elections
      - 1993 (Folder 4-5)
      - 1994 (Folder 6)
    - History
      - "Latvia, 1918-1940: Lectures by J. Grinbergs and A. L. Prams," London, 1952. Printed study (Folder 7)
      - Independence movement, 1990
        - General (Folder 8)
        - Journal of the National Independence Movement of Latvia (LNNK), 1990:, January, March, May (Folder 9)
    - Law on languages, 1989 (Folder 10)
    - Minorities
      - General (Folder 11)
      - "Report On a Fact-Finding Mission to Riga, Latvia, " by Ibrahima Fall, Director of the Centre for Human Rights, 27-30 October, 1992 (Folder 12)
    - Politics and government
      - 1987 (Folder 13)
      - 1993 (Folder 14)
    - Religion
      - General, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Religious customs (Folder 2)
  - Latvijas Tautas Fronte. Printed matter, 1988-1991 (Folder 3)
  - Refugees - Latvia
    - General, 1946 (Folder 4)
    - Printed matter, 1945-1948 (Folder 5)
    - Report cards for students in schools for Latvian refugees, 1945-1948 (Folder 6)
  - Tautas Saskanas Partijas (Folder 7)
- SERIALS, 1988-1993 (Box 2-11)
  Magazines and newspapers published in Latvia and abroad. Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Abele (Riga), Nos. 1, 2, 4, 1991: (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Adazu Ritmi, Nos. 1-3, 5-7; No. 4/5, 1991: 1992: (Folder 9)
  - Arods (Riga), Nos. 31, 32, 34-37, 1991: (Folder 10)
  - ARS (Riga), Nos. 2-10; No. 13, 1988: 1989: (Folder 11)
  - Atmata (Riga), Nos. 1-5, 1992: (Folder 12)
  - Atmoda Atputai (Riga)
    - Nos. 1-4, 1991: (Folder 13)
    - 1992
      - Nos. 27, 28, 38, 39 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Nos. 40-43 (Folder 2)
      - Nos. 44-48 (Folder 3)
      - Nos. 49-53 (Folder 4)
  - Augszeme (Jekabpili), Nos. 1, 3; Nos. 1, 3, 4, 1989: 1990: (Folder 5)
  - Auseklis (Riga), No. 1-4; Nos. 5, 6, 1987: 1988: (Folder 6)
  - Avizite (Tukuma), Nos. 4, 8-10, 1991: (Folder 7)
  - Balvu Atmoda (Balvos), No. 17, 1990: (Folder 8)
  - Ciceres Atmoda (Saldu), No. 4, 1990: (Folder 9)
  - Dailrade (Riga), No. 14, 1989: (Folder 10)
  - Demokratijas Attistibas Centrs (Riga), No. 1, 1993: (Folder 11)
  - Dienas Bizness (Riga), 1992
    - Nos. 16-18, 20-24 (Folder 12)
    - Nos. 25-30 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Nos. 31-38 (Folder 2)
  - Dziesma (Riga), 1990: February, July (Folder 3)
  - Elpa (Riga)
    - Nos. 1-8, 10-26, 1990: (Folder 4)
    - Nos. 27-37; Nos. 18, 19, 38, 41-44, 1990: 1991: (Folder 5)
    - 1992
      - Nos. 14, 15, 17-26 (Folder 6)
      - Nos. 27-30 (Folder 7)
  - Ex-Libris (Riga), Nos. 1, 2, 1991: (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Fokuss (Riga), No. 2, 1991: (Folder 2)
  - Izglitiba (Riga), 1993
    - Nos. 7-13 (Folder 3)
    - Nos. 14-20 (Folder 4)
  - Jaunais Laiks (Liepaja), Nos. 29, 32, 33, 1991: (Folder 5)
  - JIF Menedzeris (Riga), Nos. 2, 4; Nos. 5, 8, 1989: 1990: (Folder 6)
  - Junda (Riga), Nos. 1-3, 8; No. 6; No. 2, 1989: 1990: 1991: (Folder 7)
  - Kollektsioner Latvii (Riga), No. 8, 1991: (Folder 8)
  - Kriminal Vestnesis (Riga), No. 7, 1990: (Folder 9)
  - Kulturas Fonda Avize (Riga), 1991: January, May (Folder 10)
  - LaBa (Riga), Nos. 3-8, 1991: (Folder 11)
  - Laiva (Riga), Nos. 1, 4, 1992: (Folder 12)
  - Latnia (Riga), Nos. 4, 7; Nos. 12-15, 25, 26, 31, 32, 34-36, 38, 1988: 1989: (Folder 13)
  - Latvia Baltic State (Riga), 1990: July (Folder 14)
  - Latviesu Strelnieks (Riga), Nos. 5, 10, 11; Nos. 2, 4-12; Nos. 1-6, 8, 10, 1990: 1991: 1992: (Folder 15)
  - Latvijas Cels (Riga), Nos. 2, 3, 1993: (Folder 16)
  - Latvijas Jurists (Riga), No. 5, 1989: (Folder 17)
  - Latvijas Laiks (Riga), Nos. 34, 37, 39-41, 1992: (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Latvijas Menedzeris (Riga), No. 9, 1991: (Folder 2)
  - Latvijas Republikas Augstakas Padomes Un Valdibas Zinotajs (Riga), Nos. 6-9, 34/35, 1992: (Folder 3)
  - Latvijas Stradnieks (Riga), Nos. 7, 8, 1990: (Folder 4)
  - Latvijas Zalas Partijas Vestnesis (Riga), Nos. 4, 10; Nos. 12, 13, 1990: 1991: (Folder 5)
  - Latvijas Zeme (Riga), Nos. 26, 27, 1992: (Folder 6)
  - Lauku Avize (Riga)
    - No. 14; Nos. 28, 29, 1988: 1992: (Folder 7)
    - 1992
      - Nos. 30-36 (Folder 8)
      - Nos. 37-44 (Folder 9)
      - Nos. 45, 46, 48-52 (Folder 10)
  - Liepajas Vards (Riga)
    - Nos. 22/23, 45; Nos. 1-8, 10-26, 1991: 1992: (Folder 11)
    - Nos. 1-11, 1993: (Folder 12)
  - Lietiska Diena (Riga), Nos. 1-4, 6, 7, 1993: (Folder 13)
  - Literatura un Maksla (Riga), Nos. 30, 31, 33-35, 46-51, 1992: (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - LM Vestis (Riga), Nos. 10-13, 1993: (Folder 2)
  - LNNK Jelgavnieks (Riga), Nos. 19, 20; No. 22, 1990: 1991: (Folder 3)
  - LTF Informacijas Centra Vestis (Riga), Nos. 1, 3, 1990: (Folder 4)
  - LVC Informativais Biletens (Riga), April, 1990: (Folder 5)
  - Nacionala Neatkariba (Riga)
    - Nos. 1-19, 1992: (Folder 6)
    - 1993
      - Nos. 1-20 (Folder 7)
      - Nos. 21-30, 32, 33, 36-39 (Folder 8)
      - Nos. 40-44, 46-50 (Folder 9)
    - Nos. 1, 3-10, 12-14, 1994: (Folder 10)
  - Neatkariba (Riga), Nos. 7-12, 1992: (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Neatkariga Bihna (Riga), No. 188, 1991: (Folder 2)
  - Neatkariga Cina (Riga), No. 9, 1990: (Folder 3)
  - Nedelas Lapa (Riga), Nos. 3, 5, 31, 32, 1990: (Folder 4)
  - NeLLJA (Riga), 1990: April 7 (Folder 5)
  - Pavalstnieks (Riga), Nos. 1-8; Nos. 1-6, 8-10, 1992: 1993: (Folder 6)
  - Petergailis (Riga), Nos. 7, 8; Nos. 4-6, 1989: 1990: (Folder 7)
  - Pilnigi Atklati (Riga), Nos. 1, 12, 28-31, Special issue, 1992: (Folder 8)
  - Pilseta (Riga), 1991: March, July (Folder 9)
  - Pilsonis (Riga)
    - Nos. 1-17, 1990: (Folder 10)
    - 1991
      - Nos. 1-18 (Folder 11)
      - Nos. 19-34 (Folder 12)
      - Nos. 36-51 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1992
      - Nos. 1-23 (Folder 2)
      - Nos. 24-42 (Folder 3)
  - Pilsonis Pielikums (Riga), Nos. 1-7, 1992: (Folder 4)
  - Riciba (Riga), Nos. 1-13; No. 36, 1992: 1993: (Folder 5)
  - Riga Anonss (Riga), Nos. 4, 5, 1990: (Folder 6)
  - Sajudzio Zodis, No. 6, 1988: (Folder 7)
  - Sestdiena, 1991:February-April (Folder 8)
  - Sidrabavots (Riga), Nos. 3-7, 1991: (Folder 9)
  - Skauts (Riga), Nos. 9, 10, 1990: (Folder 10)
  - Socialdemokrats (Riga), Nos. 1-5; Nos. 1-6, 8; No. 9, 1989: 1990: 1991: (Folder 11)
  - Spele (Riga), Nos. 1-3, 1990: (Folder 12)
  - Sports: Latvija un Pasaule (Riga), 3 issues, 1990-1991: (Folder 13)
  - Staburags (Riga)
    - Nos. 1, 2; October/November/December, 1988: 1989: (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 1990: January/February (Folder 2)
  - Stasti un Romani (Riga), Nos. 1-3, 1992: (Folder 3)
  - Svetdienas Rits (Riga)
    - Nos. 11, 22; Nos. 5, 8-10, 12; 1, 4-6, 8-16, 1989: 1990: 1991: (Folder 4)
    - Nos. 17-24; Nos. 1, 2, 4, 5, 8, 10-14, 1991: 1992: (Folder 5)
  - Swehtdeenas Rihts (Riga), Nos. 3, 6, 7, 9, 15-24, 1992: (Folder 6)
  - Talava (Valmiera), Nos. 2, 4; No. 11, 1990: 1991: (Folder 7)
  - Tevzemes Avize (Riga), Nos. 2-5, 7-13, 32-36, 1991: (Folder 8)
  - Una Muzikas Avize (Riga), Nos. 1, 2, 4-6, 1991: (Folder 9)
  - Universitates Avize (Riga), No. 9/10, 1990: (Folder 10)
  - Vaidavina (Riga), 1991: June (Folder 11)
  - Ventas Atmoda (Riga), 1990: March, April, 14, 15 (Folder 12)
  - Vestnik Narodnogo Fronta Latvii (Riga), No. 2, 1989: (Folder 13)
  - Vieda Dabas Avize (Riga), Nos. 1-3, 5, 1991: (Folder 14)
  - Viedas Vestis (Riga), Nos. 6, 7, 1992: (Folder 15)
  - Viedoklis (Riga), No. 1, 1991: (Folder 16)
  - Zeme (Riga)
    - 1991
      - Nos. 1-24 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Nos. 25-36 (Folder 2)
    - 1992
      - Nos. 10, 28-30, 33-40 (Folder 3)
      - Nos. 41-44, 47, 48, 50 (Folder 4)
  - Ziemelblazma (Riga), No. 4, 1990: (Folder 5)
  - Ziemellatvija (Riga), Nos. 5, 9, 1990: (Folder 6)
  - Zinatnes Vestnesis (Riga), No. 12; No. 14; Nos. 1, 9, 12, 1990: 1991: 1992: (Folder 7)
- Incremental Materials (Box 12-19)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described. Contact us at hooverarchivesinfo@stanford.edu